To understand the idea of heuristics,
为了理解启发的概念
let's talk about another domain.
我们来讨论另一个领域
Here we have this sliding puzzle domain.
这里我们有一个互动拼图
Remember, we can slide around these little tiles,
记住我们可以滑动这些小方块
and we try to reach a goal state.
试图达到目标状态
16 puzzle is kind of big,
16 个拼图有些大
so let's show you the state space for the smaller 8 puzzle.
我们可以用更小的 8 个拼图
And here's just a small portion of it.
这是它的一些小份
Now, let's figure out what the action schema looks like for this puzzle.
现在我们来计算这个拼图的行动模式
So we only need to describe one action,
那么我们只需要描述一个行动
which is to slide a tile t from location a to location b,
即把方块 t 从地点 a 滑动到地点 b Slide (t, a, b)
and the precondition that the tile has to be on location A,
前提条件是 On (t, a)
and has to be a tile,
∧ Tile (t)
and B has to be blank,
∧ Blank (b)
and A and B have to be adjacent.
∧ Adj (a, b)
That should be an and sign, not an A.
这里是符号 ∧ 而不是 A
So that's the action schema.
这是动作模式
I forgot. We need an effect,
我忘了一点 我们需要一个效果
which should be that the tile is now on b and the blank is now on a,
即 On (t, b) ∧ Blank (a)
and the tile is no longer on a and the blank is no longer on b.
∧﹁On (t, a) ∧﹁Blank (b)
Now we talked before about how a human analyst could examine a problem and come up with
现在我们讨论人类分析师如何检查一个问题
heuristics and encode those heuristics as
提出启发法 把这些启发法
a function that would help search do a better job.
编码成函数 有利于更好地完成搜索
But with this kind of a formal representation,
不过利用这种形式表示法
we can automatically come up with good representations of heuristics.
我们可以自动提出较好地启发表示法
So for example, if we came up with
例如 如果我们通过
a relaxed problem by automatically going in and throwing out some of the prerequisites,
自动添加和删除一些先决条件 提出松弛问题
we threw out a prerequisite to make the problem strictly easier,
我们删除一个先决条件 让问题更加简单
then you get a new heuristic.
然后你得到一个新的启发
So for example, if we crossed out the requirement that b has to be blank,
例如我们删除要求 Blank (b)
then we end up with the Manhattan or city block heuristic.
那么我们结束于曼哈顿或城市街区
And if we also throw out the requirement that a and b have to be adjacent,
如果我们也删除 Adj (a, b)
then we get the number of misplaced tiles heuristic.
那么会得到一些错位的方块启发
So that means we could slide a tile from
这意味着无论 a 和 b 距离多远
any a to any b no matter how far apart they were.
我们都可以把方块从 a 滑到 b
That's the number of misplaced tiles.
这就是错位的方块
And other heuristics are possible.
其他启发也是可能出现的
For example, one popular thing is to ignore negative effects.
例如常见的事情是忽视负面效果
To say, let's not say that this takes away the blank being in b.
如果删除?Blank (b)
So if we ignore that negative effect we make the whole problem strictly easier.
即我们忽视了让整个问题更加简便的负面效果
We'd have a relaxed problem and that might end up being a good heuristic.
我们会得到松弛问题 最终得到较好的启发
So because we have our actions encoded in this logical form,
因为我们在这种逻辑形式中进行了编码
we can automatically edit that form.
我们可以自动编辑这个形式
A program can do that,
程序可以做到这样
and the program could come up with heuristics
程序可以提出启发法
rather than requiring the human to come up with heuristics.
而不是要求人提出启发法